Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Theater hall inside the State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara, Turkey. 23 x 31 cm, Undated; 3926; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Doors/Entrances; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; State Art and Sculpture Museum, Ankara; Architecture; Ankara, Turkey; Theater; Museums
- Selimiye Mosque, in Edirne, Turkey. View from across the nearby Tundza (Tunca) River. 23.3 x 31 cm, Undated; 3927; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Edirne, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tundzha River; Religious Sites; Selimiye Mosque; Architecture; Buildings; Mosques
- Self-portraits of Arif Hikmet Koyunoglu, the center portrait was taken in his studio Yeraltı Fotoğrafhanesi. 20.9 x 27.4 cm, 1915; 3928; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet; Yeraltı Fotoğrafhanesi, Turkey (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Facial Hair; Turkish Writing; Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Fur Garments; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair
- Woman in a dark dress and eyeglasses, emerging through a divide in a curtain. 17.6 x 12.3 cm, Undated; 3929; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet; Yeraltı Fotoğrafhanesi, Turkey (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Individual Portraits; Women; Turkey; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Hats; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Gelatin Silver Prints; Studio Photography
- Woman in a black headscarf, sitting on a chair. 17.8 x 12.3 cm, Undated; 3931; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet; Yeraltı Fotoğrafhanesi, Turkey (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Head Covers/Veils; Women; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Five soldiers of the Ottoman army ski association and two Berg Forer mountain dogs sitting on the side of the Ararat mountain during the Caucasian campaign in World War I. 9 x 14 cm, 1913; 3934; Koyunoglu, Arif Hikmet (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Animals; Military/Soldiers; Dogs; Snow; Snow Skis; Guns; Uniforms; Erzurum, Turkey; Caucasus; Turkish Writing; Wars; Ottoman Writing; World War I; Hats; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Men; Weapons; Facial Hair; Guns; Hats
- View of Nusretli, Yozgat. Berggren. 31.6 x 36.5 cm, Undated; 4090; Berggren, Guillaume (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Yozgat, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Countryside/Rural; Landscapes
- View over the Grand Bazaar. Prince Islands and Sea of Marmara. 29.8 x 37.9 cm., Undated; 4091; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Bosphorus; Prince Islands, Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Grand Bazaar; Istanbul, Turkey; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Sea of Marmara; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Religious Sites; Buildings
- Religious procession in an Ottoman village. 19.9 x 25.6 cm., Undated; 4092; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Gatherings; Religious Ceremony; Group Portraits; Buildings
- Group photo of fifteen Ottoman military men in front of a fence. Man seated in the center wearing binoculars. Man seated at the far left wearing a riding crop. 29.6 x 35.5 cm., Undated; 4093; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches; Binoculars; Uniforms
- Rifat in Samsun. "To my dear uncle Ziya Bey". 29.6 x 35.7 cm, 28 June 33 (1917); 4094; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Samsun, Turkey; Maps; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Turkish Writing; Regional/National Dress; Ottoman Writing; Men; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Uniforms
- Group portrait of three women and two men. Woman in the center holding a Turkish oud and man in the bottom right holding a shisha pipe. Photo ripped diagonally on the bottom left. 29 x 39.3 cm, Undated; 4095; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Regional/National Dress; Musical Instruments; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits; Studio Photography; Women; Men; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Facial Hair
- Port Said, Egypt. 27.9 x 35.1 cm., Undated; 4096; Arnoux, Hippolyte (Circa 1860-1890) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Landscapes; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Boats/Ships; Architecture; Port Said, Egypt; Buildings
- A portrait of a man sitting in front of a printed backdrop with a girl on his lap, a boy standing to his left. 31.4 x 25.8 cm., Undated; 4097; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Military/Soldiers; Painted Backdrops; Children; Turkey; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Weapons; Men; Uniforms; Swords/Knives; Toys; Fezes/Tarbouches; Boys; Girls; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Procession of men, horses, and carriages facing to the right with men on the right-hand side facing the center. 29.9 x 36.2 cm., Undated; 4098; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Horses; Men; Animals; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Military/Soldiers; Carriages/Coaches; Group Portraits
- Group photo of Ottoman military officials and two young boys standing underneath an archway with the Ottoman flag hanging inside the entrance to the left. 30 x 35.5 cm, Undated; 4099; Y. Nalbandian, Photographe (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Children; Facial Hair; Weapons; Ottoman Writing; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Photographic Prints; Swords/Knives; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches; Military/Soldiers; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Boys; Turkey; Arabic Writing; Men
- Group of men on horseback in traditional dress, a group of men and women in traditional dress standing and sitting on an embankment in the background, and an Ottoman soldier in uniform standing with a sword in the center foreground. 25 x 30 cm, Undated; 4100; Y. Nalbandian, Photographe (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Swords/Knives; Horses; Regional/National Dress; Women; Men; Ottoman Writing; Weapons; Animals; Turkey; Group Portraits
- Group of soldiers and government officials praying, standing at the top and base of the exterior staircase leading to the second floor terrace of a brick building. 25 x 30 cm, Undated; 4101; Y. Nalbandian, Photographe (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Facial Hair; Flags; Uniforms; Baghdad, Iraq; Swords/Knives; Facial Hair; Religious Ceremony; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Praying; Fezes/Tarbouches; Military/Soldiers; Group Portraits
- Large group of men standing to the sides of a path entering a building with striped guard towers on either side of the doorway. The men are praying, led by a religious figure in the center and a band with a drum and brass intruments stand to the right. 30 x 35.1 cm, Undated; 4102; Y. Nalbandian, Photographe (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Turkey; Weapons; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Swords/Knives; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Religious Ceremony; Praying; Military/Soldiers; Musical Instruments; Group Portraits
- A group of soldiers sit in front of their barracks, whilst a speech is given by an imam. A group of men, including German military leaders, are gathered on the right in front of a small mosque. 29.5 x 35 cm, Undated; 4103; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Religious Ceremony; Praying; Uniforms; Buildings; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Men; Architecture; Turkey; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Speeches; Religious Sites
- A line of soldiers are reviewed by visiting military leaders. 29.5 x 35 cm, Undated; 4104; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Swords/Knives; Parades/Processions; Religious Ceremony; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Turkey; Men; Regional/National Dress; Albumen Prints; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Canes/Walking Sticks; Priests/Clergymen; Group Portraits
- Cavalry class at the Ottoman Military College. Turkish writing on back reads: ("Pangalti Mekteb-i Harbiye (Ottoman Military College) 1918"). 29.5 x 30 cm, 5 June 1918; 4105; Unknown (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Military/Soldiers; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair; Hats; Uniforms
- Dr. William Goodell (1792–1867), a Christian missionary. 28.5 x 25.8 cm, 1860; 4106; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Studio Photography; Bow Ties; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Men; Albumen Prints; Turkey
- Dirt road bending to the right in the distance. The road is on the side of a hill with trees on both sides. 23.7 x 27.6 cm, Undated; 4107; Unknown (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Outdoors; Outdoors; Streets/Roads; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Landscapes
- Portrait of a man in a wool collared shirt with dark hair parted on his right, looking off to the left. 28 x 21.7 cm, 7 May 1918; 4108; Rahmizade, Bahaeddin, Mr; Studio - Photo Resna, Stamboul (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Constantinople; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits
- Mosque portal from the Nuruosmaniye Mosque with muqarnas and plaque. 26.9 x 20.9 cm, 1900; 4109; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Mosques; Nuruosmaniye Mosque; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Doors/Entrances; Arabic Calligraphy; Religious Sites; Architecture
- Studio portrait of Fazil and Fazilet. 28 x 18.9 cm, 27 September 1928; 4110; Studio - Yeni Dunya Fotografhanesi, Galata Topcilar Caddesi No. 230 (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Children; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Books; Painted Backdrops; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Girls; Boys; Istanbul, Turkey; Group Portraits
- Man with a mustache, wearing a fez and a high-collared shirt with a dark tie, looking off to the left. 24.9 x 16.6 cm, Undated; 4111; Studio - Photo Resna, Stamboul (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Studio Photography; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Individual Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Photographic Prints
- Group photo with numerous men in light-colored military uniforms, some standing and some sitting in the yard of a building among some foliage. 18.4 x 25.7 cm, Undated; 4112; Unknown (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Flags; Hand Fans; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Weapons; Men; Women; Hats; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Canes/Walking Sticks; Swords/Knives; Facial Hair
- Man with beard holding a long-handled whip, wearing high leather boots with spurs, a brimmed hat and a wide printed cummerbund around his waist. His right foot is set on a pedestal and his right hand on a tilted column. 22.6 x 21.6 cm, Undated; 4113; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Furnishings; Hats; Men
- Tree of the Janissaries in the courtyard of the Topkapi Palace. 25.6 x 20.5 cm, Circa 1894; 4114; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Buildings; Animals; Men; Topkapi Palace; Outdoors; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Sheep; Outdoors; Palaces; French Writing; Fezes/Tarbouches; Facial Hair
- Toddler girl in a light-colored lace-trimmed dress, sitting on an upholstered curule seat. Turkish writing on back: "Gift from the Armenian Patriarchate of Istanbul." 27.5 x 17.3 cm, Undated; 4222; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Children; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Turkish Writing
- Ottoman Pasha and the head guard of Wilhelm II in Baalbek. 23.6 x 30.2 cm, Undated; 4223; Akozer, Ali Sami (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Military/Soldiers; Albumen Prints; Baalbek, Lebanon; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Military/Soldiers; Men; Pasha; Weapons; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Panoramic view of Istanbul overlooking the Golden Horn. 20.5 x 26.1 cm, 1894; 4224; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Bosphorus; Istanbul, Turkey; Bridges; The Golden Horn/Haliç; Albumen Prints; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Boats/Ships; Buildings
- Entrance to Yedikule Fortress with four men standing in front with a boy seated on the bridge. 19.9 x 25.1 cm., 1860; 4225; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Children; Turkey; Boys; Street Vendors; Men; Forts/Castles; Istanbul, Turkey; Food; Food; Albumen Prints
- Tomb of Sultan Selim II with man seated on left hand side of the door and tiled art on either side. 21 x 26.9 cm., 1895; 4226; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Tombs; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Architecture; Mosques; Albumen Prints; Ottoman Writing; Arabic Calligraphy; Doors/Entrances; Religious Sites; Individual Portraits
- Nuruosmaniye Mosque Gate with street vendors. 20.9 x 26.7 cm., Circa 1890; 4227; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Arabic Calligraphy; Street Vendors; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Nuruosmaniye Mosque; Architecture; Doors/Entrances; Religious Sites; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Interior of Bayezid I Mosque (Yildirim Sultan Bayazid) with four men kneeling and chandaliers hanging low. 26.6 x 20.7 cm, 1894; 4228; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Mosques; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Ceremony; Men; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Bursa, Turkey; Religious Sites; Group Portraits; Praying; Arabic Calligraphy; Lanterns/Lamps
- The tree of the Janissaries with 3 men to the left, one man hidden in the hollow, and one man to the right of the tree. 21.8 x 26.8 cm, 1889; 4229; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Outdoors; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Topkapi Palace; Constantinople; Men; Outdoors; Istanbul, Turkey; Palaces; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Smoking
- Bayezid II Mosque exterior with pigeons in the courtyard. 21.2 x 26.8 cm., 1890; 4230; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Outdoors; Street Vendors; Men; Mosques; Birds; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Animals; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Religious Sites
- Ablution fountain outside the Bayezid II Mosque. 21.6 x 26.6 cm., 1894; 4231; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Mosques; Bayezid II Mosque; Men; Architecture; Fountains; Animals; Birds; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Religious Sites; Fountains
- Suleymaniye Mosque exterior. 20.8 x 26.9 cm., 1900; 4232; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Suleymaniye Mosque; Mosques; Religious Sites; Men; Architecture; Outdoors; Istanbul, Turkey
- Side view of Cifte Minareli Medrese with four people standing by the gate and one man standing to the left and a person carrying stacks of cloth across the street. 23.9 x 17.5 cm., Undated; 4233; Unknown (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Turkish Writing; Erzurum, Turkey; Schools/Education; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Architecture; Buildings
- Train and bridge on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 19 x 25.5 cm., Undated; 4234; Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Turkey; Bridges; Men; Trains; Photographic Prints; Pasha; Albumen Prints; Railways; Transportation
- Military Academy cadets standing before a bridge on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 25.8 x 19 cm., 1891; 4235; Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Bridges; Turkey; Railways; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Military/Soldiers; Trains; Swords/Knives; Uniforms; Pasha; Group Portraits; Transportation; Facial Hair
- Ottoman military academy students and rail workers standing in front of a train tunnel on the Istanbul-Ankara railway, opened in 1892. With General Omer Fahreddin (Pasha) Turkkan. 19 x 25.4 cm., Undated; 4236; Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Military/Soldiers; Turkey; Trains; Uniforms; Railways; Pasha; Men; Tunnels; Group Portraits; Transportation; Facial Hair; Hats
- Ottoman military academy students and railway workers standing in front of a tunnel on the Istanbul - Ankara Railway. Turkish writing on attached paper. 14.3 x 14 cm, 1891; 4237; Turkkan, Omer Fahreddin (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Turkish Writing; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Trains; Turkey; Railways; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunnels; Group Portraits; Transportation; Facial Hair; Hats
- Major General Giritli Ismail of the Ottoman cavalry. 16.8 x 23 cm, Circa 1890; 4258; Akozer, Ali Sami (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Horses; Individual Portraits; Animals; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Fezes/Tarbouches; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair
- Kaiser Wilhelm II during his visit to Umayyad Mosque in Damascus. 23.5 x 32.5 cm, 1898; 4267; Akozer, Ali Sami (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Flags; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Hats; Architecture; Mosques; Damascus, Syria; Men; Religious Sites; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Medals/Insignia
- Actors on a stage performing a production based on the battle of Sakarya. 11.5 x 17.8 cm, Undated; 4277; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Arabic Writing; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Costumes; Performance Plays; Theater; Wars; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Facial Hair
- The interior courtyard of the Manisa Sultan Mosque. 17 x 12.1 cm, Undated; 4278; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites; Men; Mosques; Manisa, Turkey; Manisa Sultan Mosque; Turkish Writing; Architecture; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Two three-masted ships in a body of water with mountains in the background. 11.9 x 16.2 cm, Undated; 4279; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Seas; Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Landscapes
- Groups of men in bowler and cylinder hats and men in traditional dress standing among a group of sitting haltered and saddled camels. 11.4 x 15.4 cm, Undated; 4280; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Men; Camels; Facial Hair; Animals; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits
- Group of seven men standing and sitting in front of the Porch of the Caryatids at the Erechtheion Temple on the north side of the Acropolis in Athens, Greece. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; 4281; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Photographic Prints; Hats; Men; The Porch of the Caryatids; Erechtheion Temple; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Albumen Prints; Athens, Greece; Acropolis of Athens; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Group of masted ships in dock, one with the name "Helios" another in the distance with a two-word name, the second of which is "Teresa" 11.9 x 16.2 cm, Undated; 4282; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Flags; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Boats/Ships; Turkey; Photographic Prints
- Man, sitting next to a sheep, smoking a pipe and a boy sitting on the curb of a street. Covered wheeled carts sit behind a fence with covers on them labeled "RUSTON PROCTOR LINCOLN ENGLAND" 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; 4283; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Photographic Prints; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Streets/Roads; Facial Hair; Animals; Children; Men; Boys; Sheep; Advertisements; Carriages/Coaches; Smoking; Turbans; Group Portraits; Tobacco pipes; Agriculture/Farms
- Fisherman standing on a boat, pulling in a net in the foreground, three two-masted ships in the background. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; 4284; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Mountains/Hills; Boats/Ships; Fishing; Individual Portraits; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Water; Boats/Ships; Men
- Two men, one in a bowler hat, talking on the street in front of a street produce market. Piles of melons are stached against the wall of a building. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; 4285; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Men; Streets/Roads; Street Vendors; Group Portraits; Food; Streets/Roads
- Five men praying on a prayer rug on the deck of a ship, one man looks directly at the camera. A lifeboat hanging in the background indicates the boat is from Liverpool. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; 4286; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Boats/Ships; Men; Praying; Sailors; Hats; Regional/National Dress; Turbans; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- The Tsar Cannon on display on the grounds of the Moscow Kremlin in Russia. A small boy sits on the pedestal on which the cannon is placed. 12 x 16.5 cm, Undated; 4287; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Kremlin (Moscow), Russia; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Boys; Gelatin Silver Prints; Moscow, Russia; Cannons; Men; Weapons
- A man in a hat and apron sitting hunched over, working on a street. Two men sit to the left, one smoking, and another man stands to the right. 12 x 16.4 cm, Undated; 4288; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Street Vendors; Streets/Roads; Men; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Hats; Smoking; Group Portraits
- Man in a hat walking across a street with a cane under his left arm. In the background, men load melons onto baskets slung over a donkey's back. 12 x 16.4 cm, Undated; 4289; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Turkey; Streets/Roads; Canes/Walking Sticks; Men; Animals; Individual Portraits; Donkeys; Architecture; Buildings; Street Lamps; Food
- Tsar Bell, Moscow, Russia. A man in a uniform stands in the foreground. 16.4 x 12 cm, Undated; 4290; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Moscow, Russia; Kremlin (Moscow), Russia; Individual Portraits; Uniforms; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Military/Soldiers
- Portrait of a standing man with mustache and goatee wearing a high light-colored collar and a three-piece. 16.4 x 12 cm, Undated; 4291; Unknown (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Men; Individual Portraits
- Mausoleum of Saladin, Damascus. 27.1 x 20.7 cm, Undated; 4292; Bonfils, Felix (Box 4, Oversize unknown container)
  Mausoleum of Saladin; Damascus, Syria; Tombs; Buildings; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Religious Sites